jobcentreonline.com 2007-12-22

# Privacy policy

This page explains how JobCentreOnline, which is managed by the Department for Employment & Learning, uses any information you give to us, and the ways in which we protect your privacy. All personal information will be dealt with in accordance with the terms of the Data Protection Act 1998.

 **The Data Protection Act**  
Under the Data Protection Act, we have a legal duty to protect any information we collect from you. We use leading technologies and encryption software to safeguard your data, and keep strict security standards to prevent any unauthorised access to it. If you make vacancy applications online, the application and CV will be passed to the relevant employer.  If you are unemployed, and make vacancy applications online, this will update your client record on our database with the vacancy number.  

 **What information do we collect?**  
We collect three kinds of information from visitors to JobCentreOnline: registration information, feedback and site usage information, from log files. In addition we are also supplied with the name and National Insurance number of successful applicants who are placed in employment. This information is processed in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and allows us to measure the effectiveness of this site.  
To ensure that the site meets the best needs of customers, and to ensure that the Department is providing the best possible service, the Department may use information for research purposes. Any research conducted will be carried out in accordance with the terms of the Data Protection Act 1998.

 **1 Registration information**  
You do not have to register to use JobCentreOnline.com, but you do need to register for certain functionality e.g. To personalise your jobsearch or to apply for vacancies online.  
The registration information we collect is: your e-mail address which acts as your username (this is unique) and a password. In addition if you are unemployed you can provide your national insurance number. Our technology supplier, Fujitsu, stores this information securely. Fujitsu keeps it so that you do not need to re-register when you come back to the site. We do not use this information to trace your identity and do not pass it on to any third party or government department.

 **2 Feedback**  
You can send us your feedback in two ways: by comments and questions to the Editor through the Feedback tab on the Home Page; or by taking part in specific targeted surveys the Department may run from time to time.  
 **i) Comments and questions**  
If you send an email or letter to the Editor, asking for information, we may need to contact other government departments to find that information. If your question is technical, we may need to pass it to our technology suppliers. We do not pass on any of your personal information when dealing with your enquiry, unless you have given us permission to do so.  
 **ii) Surveys**  
When you send comments, these may be published and read by anyone visiting the site.

 **3 Site usage information**  
i)Log files  
Log files allow us to record visitors' use of the site. Fujitsu puts together log file information from all our visitors, which we use to make changes to the layout of the site and to the information in it, based on the way that visitors move around it. Log files do not contain any personal information. JobCentreOnline stores the last time the user logged in.

 **What happens when I link to another site?**  
JobCentreOnline.com contains links to other websites, both those of government departments and of other organisations. This privacy policy applies only to our site, so you should always be aware when you are moving to another site and read the privacy statement of any site which collects personal information. We do not pass on any personal information you have given us to any other site.

 **Access to your information and contacting JobCentreOnline.com**  
You can change your registration information at any time. To do this, you should sign in then click 'My Profile' on the homepage. The 'Basic Information' button will allow you to edit your profile.  
If you have a query or complaint about this privacy policy or about the site, you can contact us by email: [mailto:jcol_feedback@delni.gov.uk](mailto:jcol_feedback@delni.gov.uk)

 **Changes to this privacy policy**  
If this privacy policy changes in any way, we will place an updated version on this page. Regularly reviewing this page ensures you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we will share it with other parties.
